

+1 347 629 1759

shariarsaimon41@gmail.com

Linkedin.com/in/shariar-islam-8497081a2

www.shariar-islam-saimon.xyz

LANGUAGE

C

C++

DART

PYTHON

JAVA SCRIPT

ENGLISH

REFERENCE

MD Rafiqul Islam Managing Director, Saimon Properties Ltd. *+8801712182967

Mr Ahnaf Abid CEO of QuickMed **(2)** +8801612946622

HOBBIES









Shariar Islam Saimon

Application Designer & Developer

Self dependent and organized individual with Bachelor's degree with honors in Computer Science and Engineering and currently pursuing Master's program in Computer Science to advance technical expertise on full stack application development. I want to be associated with a dynamic and progressive organization that will allow me to utilize my abilities and qualifications in the field to add value to the organization while providing me with opportunities for growth. I was passionate on solving problems in mathematics and programming courses. The lab classes were a highlight of my education. My blood is pumped with coding. I've done a number of projects over my college career. I started my career in the startup industry by turning my senior project, which was exhibited in the capstone, into an industrial endeavor. Later, I began my professional career as an IT manager for Saimon Properties Ltd - one of the most prestigious real estate development firms before being elevated to general manager.

EXPERIENCE

2019 - PRESENT | APP DEVELOPER | QUICKMED

A startup business initialized by me and my class mates during Bachelor program. We started our journey with the two-semester long period of planning and execution and displayed it in our Capstone. We took the professional step onward, I am in charge in the development and testing of the mobile application, executing new modules and regularly fix and update bugs in the live hosted platform. Worked with Video call integration. It's a telemedicine app (QuickMed) with features like as online video consultations with doctors, secured OTP authentication, eprescriptions, real-time chatting, electronic medical records, diagnostic tests, and drug delivery integrated with APIs, socket and payment gateway, PostgreSQL object-relation database system, Django framework(python) for web application and flutter(dart) for mobile applications (Android, IOS).

2020-PRESENT GENERAL MANAGER SAIMON **PROPERTIES LTD**

I have started as an IT specialist in the company, I myself developed and deployed the website of the company. Currently working on a ERP software for the company, in short it will work as an e-office. Besides, I have been the admin of the social platforms and generating leads. Recently, being the General Manager I have been active in the marketing and advertisement of the company and its projects.

EDUCATION

2022 - Present: Master's in Computer Science

University of Bridgeport, CT, USA

Major: Computer Science

CGPA: 4.00

2015 - 2019: Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering

North South University, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Major: CSE (Computer Science and Engineering)

CGPA: 3.24

Relevant Coursework: Machine learning, Artificial Intelligence, Internet and web technology, Database Management System, Software engineering.

2012 - 2014 A' Levels

Hurdco International School, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Curriculum: Cambridge (CIE)

SKILLS

Android/IOS	Web Development	Application Design
Machine Learning & AI	HTML/CSS	Team Work
Digital Marketing	Verilog (HDL)	Oracle



- (8) +1 347 629 1759
- shariarsaimon41@gmail.com
- 575 D, Atlantic Street, Bridgeport, CT, 06604,
- Linkedin.com/in/shariar-islam-8497081a2
- www.shariar-islam-saimon.xyz

LANGUAGE

C
C++

DART

PYTHON

JAVA SCRIPT

REFERENCE

ENGLISH

MD Rafiqul Islam
Managing Director,
Saimon Properties Ltd.
& +8801712182967

Mr Ahnaf Abid CEO of QuickMed & +8801612946622

HOBBIES









Shariar Islam Saimon

ACTIVITIES

- Working as Summer Assistant in Residential Housing of University of Bridgeport.
- Worked as Front Desk Assistant in Residential Housing of University of Bridgeport.
- Worked on an ERP software for a real estate company (Saimon Properties Ltd.).
- Got Certified from Creative It Institution upon completion of Web Development course
- Alumni member at North South University Computer and Engineering Club (NSU CEC)
- Daily Star Awardee of excellent result in A' levels 2013-14
- Freelancing in local citation for hotels in USA, Canada
- Teaching experience of more than 5 years (O' Levels and A' Levels).
- Volunteer at Youth Wave Foundation (2014).